Grégoire Mialon

2017 - 2018

	École Normale Supérieure Département Informatique Paris, France		gregoire.mialon@inria.fr https://github.com/GregoireMialon https://gregoiremialon.github.io
Research			
2018 - <i>Now</i>		 Inria / École Normale Supérieure (Paris, France) - PhD student Member of Sierra team and Thoth team. Building machine learning models that learn with few labeled data. Also working on NLP and Causal Inference. Advisors: Pr. Julien Mairal, Pr. Alexandre d'Aspremont. 	
2016 (5 mor	nths)	Massachussets Institute of Technology (Cambridge, MA) - Research Intern - Nuclear Science and Engineering, Offshore Floating Nuclear Plant group Built a fast model for predicting damage resulting from ship collisions using finite elements and high performance computing Managers: Pr. Neil Todreas, Pr. Koroush Shirvan.	
Education			
2017 - 2018		- Founded in 1996, it is the oldest Machine Learning in France.	Isc. Mathematics, Vision and Learning (MVA) and most prestigious Master's program in p Learning, Natural Language Processing (NLP).
2013 - 2017		 École polytechnique (Palaiseau, France) - Graduate Student Founded in 1794, the École polytechnique is the most prestigious Science and Engineering university in France, with a strong focus on Applied Mathematics. Majored in Theoretical Physics and Economics. Minored in Business Studies and Entrepreneurship. 	
2010 - 2013		,	- Preparatory Classes: Bachelor level es, Physics to prepare top-level science
Job experience			
2019 - 2020		Athling (Paris, France) - Consultant Evaluating the impact of machine learning on commerce and distribution. This report was commissioned by the french Prospective Observatory for Trade.	
2018 - 2020		Université Paris-Dauphine (Figure Python for Data Science and Mach	

eXplain (Paris, France) - Data Scientist, NLP

presidential elections.

- eXplain (ex-Liegey Muller Pons) is a company focusing on electoral campaign technology. The company closely worked for the last two winners of the french

- Developed and sold an automated press analysis product relying on NLP.

- Managers: Pr. Vincent Pons, Arthur Muller (founders).

2016 - 2017 Lycée Saint-Louis (Paris, France) - Teaching Assistant in Preparatory Classes

Tutored and tested weekly students in physics for nationwide examination.

2015 (3 months) Ministry for Foreign Affairs (Paris, France) - Civil Servant Intern

- Drafted notes on terrorism for diplomats and political leaders on a mission.

- Manager: Emmanuel Cocher.

Publications and pre-prints

- G. Mialon*, D. Chen*, A. d'Aspremont and J. Mairal. An Optimal Transport Kernel for Feature Aggregation and its Relationship to Attention *(under review)*.
- G. Mialon, A. d'Aspremont and J. Mairal. Screening Data Points for Empirical

Risk Minimization via Ellipsoidal Regions and Safe Loss Functions (AISTATS 2020).

- A. Bietti*, G. Mialon*, D. Chen and J. Mairal. A Kernel Perspective for Regularizing Deep Neural Networks (ICML 2019).

Past projects

During Msc. MVA:

- Data Challenge: Predicting cancer from DNA for Stéphane Mallat's Curse of Dimensionality course 2018 (ranked first decile).
- Built a Tweet normalizer and a Parser for Emmanuel Dupoux's NLP course.
- Primal and dual solvers for the SVM problem for Alexandre d'Aspremont's Convex Optimization course.

See GitHub for implementations.

During Graduate Level:

- Data Challenge: RAMP Drug Test Challenge 2017 (ranked first decile).
- Data Challenge: AXA Data Challenge 2016 (ranked first quartile).

Awards and Fellowships

2016 EDF Énergies nouvelles Fellowship - for pursuing research at MIT.

2016 École polytechnique Outstanding Investment - for involvment in the campus life and in a microfinance non-profit organization.

Languages and Skills

French (mother tongue), English (TOEIC: 965/990), German (advanced). Python (advanced), Rowing (involved in student contests).